<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Liberty Live Church</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>It&#039;s not just church, it&#039;s life</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 17:45:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/LLC-App-Icon-Black-40x40.jpg</url>
	<title>Liberty Live Church</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s Happening at Liberty This Spring?</title>
		<link>/2022/03/07/blog-whatshappeningatlibertythisspring/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 17:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Jehovah: Names of God]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=19046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Praise God for what He did in our services on Sunday! It was so good to worship together. The Jehovah Names of God series has been such an encouragement to me so far and I pray it has been to you as well. Next week I will post on Jehovah-Rohi, but for now I wanted...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/03/07/blog-whatshappeningatlibertythisspring/">What&#8217;s Happening at Liberty This Spring?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Praise God for what He did in our services on Sunday! It was so good to worship together. The Jehovah Names of God series has been such an encouragement to me so far and I pray it has been to you as well. Next week I will post on Jehovah-Rohi, but for now I wanted to mention some exciting things that are coming in the months ahead.</p>
<p>First, this weekend we set our clocks back. I know that’s not all that exciting because we lose an hour of sleep, but we will have donuts for you when you get to church! Come hungry! We will also be looking at what it means that God is Jehovah-Tsidkenu, God my Righteousness. It will be a great day!</p>
<p>Easter is just over a month away. Our Good Friday service will be at 7:00 p.m. Then, our Easter services begin at 5:00 p.m. on Saturday. The Sunday service times are 7:30, 9:00, and 10:45 a.m. for Hampton, Harbour View, Greenbrier, and York River. Smithfield and Gloucester will have services at 9:00 and 10:45 a.m. Make plans now to invite your family and friends and join us!</p>
<p>Additionally, more <em>Goodbye Fear</em> books have been ordered! The response was overwhelming right before Christmas and we are excited to let you know that more will be in right around Easter. Stay tuned for announcements on when you can purchase. They are still only $5 and make great gifts! (Side note: if you missed the announcement on Sunday, the <em>Parenting Your Parents</em> book goes through Psalm 23, which is where we read about Jehovah-Rohi, God my Shepherd. You can find it <a href="https://store.libertylive.church/product/parenting-your-parents/">here</a>).</p>
<p>April 30-May 7 is 757 Strong Week. While we serve our community all year, this is a week that we really focus on taking the church to the cities around us. Talk to your group, family, or friends and start thinking about what you can do to make a difference in the name of Jesus.</p>
<p>Spring is a time of new life and growth. God has certainly been at work in 2022 and I am praying that this spring we will see that spiritual new life and growth continue.</p>
<p>The best is yet to come!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/03/07/blog-whatshappeningatlibertythisspring/">What&#8217;s Happening at Liberty This Spring?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Does Jehovah-Nissi mean? – Exodus 17</title>
		<link>/2022/03/03/blog-whatdoesjehovahnissimean/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 17:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Jehovah: Names of God]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=19049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When you meet someone, one of the first questions you ask is, “What’s your name?” That is how friendships and relationships begin. Most of us have more than one name depending on the relationship of the person addressing us. Our names tell who we are to that person. Similarly, the names of God reveal who...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/03/03/blog-whatdoesjehovahnissimean/">What Does Jehovah-Nissi mean? – Exodus 17</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you meet someone, one of the first questions you ask is, “What’s your name?” That is how friendships and relationships begin. Most of us have more than one name depending on the relationship of the person addressing us. Our names tell who we are to that person. Similarly, the names of God reveal who He is to us and who He desires to be in our lives. In Genesis 1:1 we see God as Elohim, the Creator. “In the beginning God created the heavens and the earth.” God is eternal. He created all things and He knows all things. In Genesis 2 we see God as Jehovah, which is His personal name. Genesis 2:4 says, “This is the account of the heavens and the earth when they were created, when the LORD God made the earth and the heavens.” God is Creator but He is not some impersonal force or power who is distant. God is personal. He desires to know us on a personal level and He wants us to know Him. He desires a relationship with His creation. You can believe in Elohim (there is a God) and not believe in Jehovah (know Him personally).</p>
<p>Throughout the Old Testament, God is known by many names. Many of those names compound with Jehovah, telling us more about God, His character, and who He desires to be in our lives. That is exactly what we see in Exodus 17 with Jehovah-Nissi, God our Victory.</p>
<p><strong>In Times of Weariness</strong><br />
Exodus 17 is where we read this name for the first time. The Israelites complained to Moses, “Give us water to drink” (v. 2). They were camping in the wilderness and there was no water. Moses brought their complaint before the Lord and in verse 6 we see the Lord say, “I am going to stand there in front of you on the rock at Horeb; when you hit the rock, water will come out of it and the people will drink.” First Corinthians 10:4 says that rock was Christ, the solid rock, the cornerstone that was struck, beaten, and crucified on the cross. John 7 says the water is a picture of the Holy Spirit. The Israelites had traveled in the hot, dry, desert with wind and sand, and they were thirsty. They were weary. Don’t grow weary in well doing. Jehovah-Nissi will enable you to run and not be weary, to walk and not faint. When you are weary God is your victory, Jehovah-Nissi. The name means the LORD is our banner, mighty warrior, victory. A banner today is like a sign or flag. You see them often at sporting events to show whose team you are for. Moses wanted to remind God’s people that our allegiance is ultimately to the LORD. God alone gives us the victory.</p>
<p><strong>In Times of Warfare</strong><br />
Right after God gives the Israelites water from the rock, we read, “At Rephidim, Amalek came and fought against Israel” (v. 8). Rephidim means place of rest. The enemy will hit you when you are hungry, thirsty, defenseless, and you let down your guard. In this story, Moses stood on the hilltop and as long as his hands were lifted, Israel prevailed. Aaron and Hur helped Moses keep his hands up and “Joshua defeated Amalek and his army with the sword” (v. 13). This reminds me of Psalm 63:4, “I will praise you as long as I live, and in your name I will lift up my hands.” What happens on the hilltop determines the outcome in the valley. Fight the good fight of faith. Pray and fight for your marriage, children, business, and testimony. The arm of flesh alone will fail. Find an Aaron and a Hur who will agree with you in prayer. Our God is mighty to save, mighty in battle. He is our defender, our shield, our fortress, our refuge. No wonder Proverbs 18:10 says, “The name of the LORD is a strong tower; The righteous run to it and are safe.”</p>
<p><strong>In Times of Worship</strong><br />
The chapter ends, “And Moses built an altar and named it, ‘The LORD Is My Banner.’ He said, ‘Indeed, my hand is lifted up toward the LORD’S throne. The LORD will be at war with Amalek from generation to generation’” (v. 15-16). The battle is the LORD’s. God will contend/fight with those who contend with you. You get under the banner of the Lordship of Jesus Christ and He will give you the victory!</p>
<p>First John 5:4 says, “This is the victory that has overcome the world, even our faith.” First Corinthians 15:57 says, “But thanks be to God! He gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.” Moses knew Jehovah brought the victory and gave God all the glory. Look to Jehovah-Nissi today for your victory.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/03/03/blog-whatdoesjehovahnissimean/">What Does Jehovah-Nissi mean? – Exodus 17</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Baptism?</title>
		<link>/2022/02/23/blog-whatisbaptism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 14:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Baptism today can mean a variety of things to a variety of people. Some people are baptized as a baby, some are sprinkled with water, and some are fully immersed. Some people believe baptism is what saves you and others say it’s an outward sign of an inward transformation. Today, we are going to look...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/23/blog-whatisbaptism/">What is Baptism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Baptism today can mean a variety of things to a variety of people. Some people are baptized as a baby, some are sprinkled with water, and some are fully immersed. Some people believe baptism is what saves you and others say it’s an outward sign of an inward transformation. Today, we are going to look at what the Bible says, and look at Jesus’ baptism, in order to see the truth. The baptism of Jesus is so important it is recorded in all four gospels (Matt. 3, Mk. 1, Lk. 3, Jn 1). As we look at His baptism, we’ll see:</p>
<p><strong>The Action of Jesus</strong><br />
“It came to pass in those days that Jesus came from Nazareth of Galilee, and was <strong>baptized</strong> by John in the Jordan. And immediately, <strong>coming up</strong> from the water, He saw the heavens parting and the Spirit descending upon Him like a dove. Then a voice came from heaven, ‘You are My beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased’” (Mk. 1:9-11). Mark uses the word “baptize” six times in the first nine verses of this chapter. “Baptizo” means to dip repeatedly, to immerse, to submerge. Notice the verse above says that Jesus came up from the water, meaning that He had to go down in it. The account in John 3 says, “there was much water there.” Baptism is a picture of death, burial, and resurrection, and you can’t get that picture out of sprinkling a few drops of water.</p>
<p>Who should be baptized? When we read about baptism in the New Testament, however old each person was, they were old enough to believe. It was not something their parents or families did for them. In Acts, they <strong>believed</strong> and were baptized. Baptism is only for believers. It comes after repentance. If your baptism did not mark death to the old life and the beginning of a new life then it was not New Testament, believer’s baptism. </p>
<p>Jesus was baptized to set an example and identify with us. Jesus died for us, was buried for us, and rose from the dead for us. If only one word described baptism it is “identification.” We are baptized to identify with Jesus. Jesus was baptized and He commanded all His followers to be baptized. </p>
<p><strong>The Anointing of the Holy Spirit</strong><br />
“When all the people were being <strong>baptized</strong>, Jesus was baptized too. And as he was <strong>praying</strong>, heaven was opened and the <strong>Holy Spirit</strong> descended on him in bodily form like a dove” (Lk. 3:21-22). Some translations will say the heavens were <strong>torn open</strong>. The word occurs only one other time in Mark’s Gospel when the temple curtain was torn open from top to bottom at the crucifixion of Jesus. It was a fulfillment of the Old Testament prophecy in Isaiah, “If only you would (rend) tear the heavens open and come down…” (Is. 64:1). He did!!! God came to earth as Jesus, and we now have access to the Father through Jesus. John the Baptist said in Mark 1:8, “I <strong>baptize</strong> you with <strong>water</strong>, but he will baptize you with the <strong>Holy Spirit</strong>.” When you put your trust in Jesus, God puts the Holy Spirit inside of you. The baptism of the Holy Spirit is not reserved for a select few. In Acts 10:47, Peter was about to baptize the first Gentile, Cornelius. He said, “Can anyone forbid water, that these should not be <strong>baptized</strong> who have received the <strong>Holy Spirit</strong> just as we have?” Baptism is an outward sign of an inward experience. </p>
<p><strong>The Approval of the Father</strong><br />
Matthew 3:17 tells us, “And a voice from heaven said, ‘This is my Son, whom I love; with him I am well pleased.’” Jesus is the Son of God. In the gospels He forgives sin, heals the sick, casts out demons, raises the dead, and Himself rises from the dead. He is the second Adam who came to restore what the first Adam lost (Rom. 5:12-15). Baptism is central to our message and mission. In Matthew 28:18-19, we read, “And Jesus came and spoke to them, saying, ‘All authority has been given to Me in heaven and on earth. Go therefore and make disciples of all the nations, <strong>baptizing</strong> them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.” Baptism is not optional. It is a command of Christ for every believer. If you want to please God, you will be baptized. You want the Father to look down and say, “This is my son/daughter with whom I am well pleased.” The pattern of baptism in the New Testament is also immediate. When we look at Acts 2, people repented and were baptized the same day. </p>
<p>Salvation is in Jesus alone. It’s not in Jesus plus religion, baptism, communion, or good works. It is in Jesus alone. Baptism does not save a person, but every saved person should be baptized.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/23/blog-whatisbaptism/">What is Baptism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do You Know Where You&#8217;ll Spend Eternity?</title>
		<link>/2022/02/16/blog-doyouknowwhereyoullspendeternity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 14:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sunday was an unforgettable day with Coach Mark Richt! He did an incredible job sharing his faith and the gospel. It was so encouraging to see people back that we haven’t seen since COVID, as well as so very many new faces. If you missed the service on Sunday, click here to watch now. I...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/16/blog-doyouknowwhereyoullspendeternity/">Do You Know Where You&#8217;ll Spend Eternity?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sunday was an unforgettable day with Coach Mark Richt! He did an incredible job sharing his faith and the gospel. It was so encouraging to see people back that we haven’t seen since COVID, as well as so very many new faces. If you missed the service on Sunday, click <a href="/messages/">here</a> to watch now.</p>
<p>I keep thinking about how Coach Richt came to know the Lord. When he was on the coaching staff at Florida State, one of the players, Pablo Lopez, was tragically killed. The next day as Head Coach Bobby Bowden addressed the team, he asked them to put themselves in Pablo’s shoes. He asked them if it would have been them who died, do they know where they’d spend eternity? God spoke to Coach Richt through Coach Bowden and he gave his life to Christ.</p>
<p>I asked the Liberty family the same question on Sunday. No one is guaranteed tomorrow. Every one of us will die and when we do, the only decision that will matter is whether or not we’ve put our faith in Jesus.</p>
<p>Will you put yourself in Pablo’s shoes? Do you know where you will spend eternity? If not, like Coach Richt did so many years ago, I encourage you to get it settled today.</p>
<p>You may say, “I am as good as the people who go to church.”<br />
We do not compare ourselves to others but to God. None of us measure up.</p>
<p>You may say, “There are hypocrites in the church.”<br />
I agree. There are in every walk of life. Just because there are bad restaurants doesn’t not keep you from eating!</p>
<p>You may say, “I am going to wait.”<br />
For what? God is not going to write another Bible and Jesus is not going to die again on the cross.</p>
<p>You may say, “I’m not worthy.”<br />
No one is but Jesus.</p>
<p>You may say, “I can’t live the Christian life.”<br />
It is not about rules. It is about a relationship.</p>
<p>You may say, “I am too busy.”<br />
You are not too busy to go to work, school, a ballgame, or to die.</p>
<p>You may say, “I have my own religion.”<br />
It is not the Baptist, Methodist, Catholic, Pentecostal, or any other way. Jesus said, “I am the way….”</p>
<p>You may say, “I am not ready to join the church.”<br />
You are right. You have to first trust Jesus. Trusting in Jesus does not automatically make you a church member.</p>
<p>You may say, “I have tried but failed.”<br />
You may have tried religion, or good works, but Jesus never fails.</p>
<p>You may say, “I like my life the way it is.”<br />
Will you like it 20 or 40 years from now? Will you like it when you die?</p>
<p>One day we are all going to watch our last Super Bowl. Sunday night was the last Super Bowl some people will ever watch. Your accomplishments in life, your career, your money, will not matter when it is your time to die. All that matters is whether you name is written in God’s record book.</p>
<p>Yesterday was Valentine’s Day. Every married couple knows how it all begins. Someone makes a proposal, and someone says, “Yes.” Jesus has made a proposal in His Word. Romans 10:13 says, “For everyone who calls on the name of the Lord will be saved.” Will you call on His name and say “yes” to Him today?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/16/blog-doyouknowwhereyoullspendeternity/">Do You Know Where You&#8217;ll Spend Eternity?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Where is His ‘Coming’ That He Promised?” (2 Peter 3:4) – 2 Peter 3</title>
		<link>/2022/02/08/blog-whereishiscomingthathepromised/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 18:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jesus is coming again. There are 260 chapters in the New Testament and the Second Coming of Christ is mentioned 318 times. The last prayer of the Bible is, “Even so come, Lord Jesus.” His coming is in two phases/movements. He is coming to the clouds. Then He is coming to the earth and His...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/08/blog-whereishiscomingthathepromised/">“Where is His ‘Coming’ That He Promised?” (2 Peter 3:4) – 2 Peter 3</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jesus is coming again. There are 260 chapters in the New Testament and the Second Coming of Christ is mentioned 318 times. The last prayer of the Bible is, “Even so come, Lord Jesus.” His coming is in two phases/movements. He is coming to the clouds. Then He is coming to the earth and His feet will touch the Mount of Olives. He is coming FOR His saints. Then He is coming WITH His saints. There will be a resurrection, rapture, and reunion according to 1 Thessalonians 4. In 2 Peter 3, Peter is giving reminders about the last day. Many people today wonder, &#8220;is it the end of the world?&#8221; We don’t know, but what we do know is that it is the world of the end. What do we need to remember in light of His return?</p>
<p><strong>Remember His Worship</strong><br />
Peter tells us in verse 1 that he is seeking to “stir up” understanding “by way of reminder.” He has told the people this before, but they need reminding. This world is not our final destination or our home. It is just the layover! We are just passing through. It’s easy to get distracted and lose focus. We should have our devotions every morning and then ask the Holy Spirit to remind us throughout the day and to stir up and stimulate our thinking toward heaven. Additionally, we should not forsake “the assembling of ourselves together” as the writer of Hebrews states (Heb. 10:25). He says we should “consider one another in order to stir up love and good works” and we should exhort one another “so much the more as you see the Day approaching” (Heb. 10:24-25). Why should we do this? The closer we get to that day the more Christians will be under persecution. We need one another.</p>
<p><strong>Remember His Word</strong><br />
Peter goes on to encourage the church to remember the words “previously spoken by the holy prophets and the command of our Lord and Savior given through [the] apostles” (v. 2). He says scoffers will come and will question the validity of Jesus’ promise of His coming, but God’s word is powerful and He has done before what He said He’ll do (v. 3-6). When God speaks, things happen! The promise of His coming can be found in the Old Testament, the Gospels, Acts, the Epistles, and Revelation. By His word we can know for certain He is coming again!</p>
<p><strong>Remember His Witness </strong><br />
Additionally, Peter offers insight as to why it’s seemingly taking so long for the Lord to return. “The Lord does not delay his promise, as some understand delay, but is patient with you, not wanting any to perish but all to come to repentance” (v. 9). In our world of instant gratification, we need some perspective. How many years were there from Malachi to Matthew? 400! According to the Jewish calendar there are nearly 4,000 years from Adam to Christ. 2,000 years have passed since Jesus promised to return. That is less than half as long as the Old Testament saints waited! Peter says to “regard the patience of our Lord as salvation” (v. 15). So often we can get caught up in the timeline of end-time events, but what really matters to God is people. What if you are right about all your timetables but you are not ready? What if you have it all figured out, but your family and friends are not ready?</p>
<p><strong>Remember His Work</strong><br />
Ultimately, “the day of the Lord will come like a thief” and this earth will pass away (v. 10). “Therefore, dear friends, while you wait for these things, make every effort to be found without spot or blemish in his sight, at peace” (v. 14). We will all stand before the judgement seat of Christ where we will give an account of our lives on this earth (1 Cor. 3:13, 2 Cor. 5:10). I am working to hear the Master say, “‘Well done, good and faithful servant; you were faithful over a few things, I will make you ruler over many things. Enter into the joy of your lord’” (Mt. 25:21). How do you want to be found when He comes?</p>
<p>There is more to this life than this life. What you believe about the Lord’s return determines how you live today. Is what you are giving your life to going to show up in eternity?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/08/blog-whereishiscomingthathepromised/">“Where is His ‘Coming’ That He Promised?” (2 Peter 3:4) – 2 Peter 3</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Scriptures Talk About The Return of Jesus?</title>
		<link>/2022/02/06/whatscripturestalkaboutthereturnofjesus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 19:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here are some of the slides from this morning showing where we read in the Old Testament, the Gospels, the book of Acts, the Epistles and the book of Revelation, about the Lord&#8217;s return. *Adapted from Francis Dixon’s Bible Study Notes.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/06/whatscripturestalkaboutthereturnofjesus/">What Scriptures Talk About The Return of Jesus?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here are some of the slides from this morning showing where we read in the Old Testament, the Gospels, the book of Acts, the Epistles and the book of Revelation, about the Lord&#8217;s return.</p>
<p><a ref="magnificPopup" href="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-18883" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-1030x579.jpg 1030w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-600x337.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-500x281.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-400x225.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-700x394.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-800x450.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-900x506.jpg 900w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-200x112.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-100x56.jpg 100w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-70x39.jpg 70w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-50x28.jpg 50w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_20-60x34.jpg 60w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><a ref="magnificPopup" href="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-18884" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-1030x579.jpg 1030w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-600x337.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-500x281.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-400x225.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-700x394.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-800x450.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-900x506.jpg 900w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-200x112.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-100x56.jpg 100w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-70x39.jpg 70w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-50x28.jpg 50w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_21-60x34.jpg 60w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><a ref="magnificPopup" href="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-18885" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-1030x579.jpg 1030w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-600x337.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-500x281.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-400x225.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-700x394.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-800x450.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-900x506.jpg 900w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-200x112.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-100x56.jpg 100w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-70x39.jpg 70w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-50x28.jpg 50w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_22-60x34.jpg 60w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><a ref="magnificPopup" href="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-18886" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-1030x579.jpg 1030w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-600x337.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-500x281.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-400x225.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-700x394.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-800x450.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-900x506.jpg 900w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-200x112.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-100x56.jpg 100w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-70x39.jpg 70w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-50x28.jpg 50w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/20220130_23-60x34.jpg 60w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>*Adapted from Francis Dixon’s Bible Study Notes.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/06/whatscripturestalkaboutthereturnofjesus/">What Scriptures Talk About The Return of Jesus?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Do I Experience God’s All-Sufficient Grace? – 2 Corinthians 12:2-10</title>
		<link>/2022/02/02/blog-howdoiexperiencegodsallsufficientgrace/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 16:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2 Corinthians 12, Paul is struggling through a situation and the Lord tells him, “My grace is sufficient for you, for My strength is made perfect in weakness.” As we read Paul’s story, we too can discover how to experience the all-sufficient grace that God promises. There are five scenes or movements in Paul’s...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/02/blog-howdoiexperiencegodsallsufficientgrace/">How Do I Experience God’s All-Sufficient Grace? – 2 Corinthians 12:2-10</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2 Corinthians 12, Paul is struggling through a situation and the Lord tells him, “My grace is sufficient for you, for My strength is made perfect in weakness.” As we read Paul’s story, we too can discover how to experience the all-sufficient grace that God promises. There are five scenes or movements in Paul’s life we see in this passage:</p>
<p><strong>Paradise</strong><br />
In verses 2-5 we read that Paul had a heavenly experience. We aren’t given the exact details of how, but we know it was 14 years earlier. Paradise is only mentioned three times in the New Testament (here, Luke 23:43, and Revelation 2:7) and each time it refers to heaven. In verse 6 he says that he will not boast so that no one would credit him. When we go through hard times, it often seems as if God is not answering our prayers. We wonder, what if the miracle doesn’t come? Paul did not take the credit for this great experience. We can rest in knowing we don’t take the credit if the miracle happens, and we don’t take the criticism if the miracle does not happen. We pray and leave it in God’s hands. We pray, “Your Kingdom come, Your will be done on earth as it is in heaven.”</p>
<p><strong>Pain</strong><br />
Paul continues, “so that I would not exalt myself, a thorn in the flesh was given to me, a messenger of Satan to torment me so that I would not exalt myself” (v. 7). In this story we read about God and Satan, heaven and a messenger from hell, mentioned in the same passage. God has balanced life with mountain tops and valleys. It can be the best of times and the worst of times all at the same time. Just as God permitted Satan to tempt Adam and Eve, Job, and Peter, he permitted Satan to attack Paul. God even uses Satan to accomplish God’s purposes. We aren’t told the details of Paul’s thorn, but you know yours! All of us have problems and weaknesses. We can resent our thorn and fight it, or we can embrace it and accept it. Don’t let your pain make you a bitter person. Let it make you a better person.</p>
<p><strong>Purpose</strong><br />
Twice the purpose of the thorn is stated – “so that I would not exalt myself.” It was to keep Paul humble and useable. The purpose was to deliver him from being spiritually proud. He could have bragged about his heavenly experience, but he didn’t. Blessings are dangerous. To whom much is given, much is required. God allowed this to keep Paul useable and it worked! Paul would be much more fruitful this way. Self-sufficient stands in the way of an all-sufficient God. God takes what is broken and, like a recycling plant, makes it useable again. Paul did not simply make the best of it. He made the most of it.</p>
<p><strong>Prayer</strong><br />
Paul says, “I pleaded with the Lord three times that it would leave me” (v. 8). It drove Paul to his knees. He prayed like Jesus in Gethsemane. Paul prayed and pleaded and begged God. Have you ever had your kids beg for something that you know would not ultimately be for their good? There is no problem God cannot solve and no prayer He cannot answer. He may not answer it the way you think it should be answered, but He is a loving Father and can be trusted.</p>
<p><strong>Power</strong><br />
It turns out God answered Paul’s prayer, but not in the way he thought. “But he said to me, ‘My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is perfected in weakness.’ Therefore, I will most gladly boast all the more about my weaknesses, so that Christ’s power may reside in me. So I take pleasure in weaknesses, insults, hardships, persecutions, and in difficulties, for the sake of Christ. For when I am weak, then I am strong” (v. 9-10). We can learn from Paul. We can pray and pour out our hearts to God and then listen and accept His answer. Whatever the pain Paul experienced, God’s grace was more. The greatest revelation was not the glory of Heaven, but the grace of heaven.</p>
<p>God’s statement to Paul was, “My grace is sufficient.” “Is” is present tense. He didn’t say it “will be,” “ought to be,” or “can be,” but that it is. Should a fish be worried about there not being enough water in the ocean? No. There is never a shortage of water in the ocean and there is never a shortage of God’s grace. It IS sufficient and it always will be.</p>
<p>Weakness is the stage on which God displays His power. God does not use us in spite of our weaknesses but because of our weaknesses. Paul said he would “gladly boast” in his weakness. The word means shout! Anyone can praise God when everything goes their way. Will you praise Him when you are hurting, in pain? “Power” here means to spread a tent over. When you are weak God will tabernacle over you and you will feel His presence and power like never before.</p>
<p>You say, “But I have pain and I have prayed but I have not experienced all-sufficient grace. Why?” Three things are necessary. First, you must have a thorn in the flesh – pain, agony. Second, you must have unanswered prayers – mystery. Third, and this is where it gets hard, you must glory (gladly boast) in your infirmities. That’s when you experience the victory!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/02/02/blog-howdoiexperiencegodsallsufficientgrace/">How Do I Experience God’s All-Sufficient Grace? – 2 Corinthians 12:2-10</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Should I Trust God? – Proverbs 3:5-13</title>
		<link>/2022/01/26/blog-whyshoulditrustgod/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 11:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes it’s hard to trust God. It’s hard to choose His way over our own and to obey when things may not make sense. Proverbs 3:5 says, “Trust in the Lord with all your heart, and lean not on your own understanding.” Trust is the idea of confidence. It means “to throw your back on,”...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/01/26/blog-whyshoulditrustgod/">Why Should I Trust God? – Proverbs 3:5-13</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes it’s hard to trust God. It’s hard to choose His way over our own and to obey when things may not make sense. Proverbs 3:5 says, “Trust in the Lord with all your heart, and lean not on your own understanding.” Trust is the idea of confidence. It means “to throw your back on,” just like you would sit on a chair or lay on a bed with your full weight. We do not always understand the will and ways of God, but we can lean hard on Jesus! Abraham taking Isaac to Mount Moriah did not make sense but that is where the ram was. Elijah by the brook Cherith did not make sense but that is where the raven came! As we look at the rest of this passage in Proverbs 3, we’ll see that the God who guided Abraham and Moses and Elijah wants to guide us. When we trust Him, he promises to direct, provide for, and correct us, just like He did for them.</p>
<p><strong>The Promise of Direction</strong><br />
Verse 6 says, “In all your ways acknowledge Him, and He shall direct your paths.” God’s thoughts are not our thoughts and His ways are not our ways (Is. 55:8). Whenever I drive, I use a navigation app called Waze. It let’s me know what’s coming ahead – objects in the road, accidents, or police officers. We need the “Waze” of God! Have you ever been in a new place and asked a total stranger for directions? We trust total strangers, we trust doctors, lawyers, bankers, but we struggle to trust God. If you are trusting in yourself, God cannot guide you. Look at the repeated word “all” in verses 5-6. The Christian life is not a way of looking at certain things, it is a certain way of looking at all things! When you obey the direction God has given, God will reveal the future to you one step at a time. Life is filled with twists and turns. You don’t know what is coming around the next bend. There are no signposts to help us navigate. “Path” indicates a destination. We are going somewhere! Not only is God leading but He is clearing the way. He will make your path straight when you trust Him in all things.</p>
<p><strong>The Promise of Provision</strong><br />
The passage continues, “Do not be wise in your own eyes; Fear the Lord and depart from evil. It will be health to your flesh, and strength to your bones. Honor the Lord with your possessions, and with the firstfruits of all your increase; So your barns will be filled with plenty, and your vats will overflow with new wine” (v. 7-10). When the Lord is your Shepherd, you shall not want. He gives us each day our daily bread. He provides what money cannot buy, your health. Add up everything that money cannot buy, a calculator cannot compute, and death cannot take away, and that is how wealthy you really are. These verses we read are Solomon’s advice to David. It’s advice on money from the wisest and one of the wealthiest men who ever lived. “Firstfruits” is giving God our best first, not our leftovers. Give God the first hour of every day, the first day of every week, and the first dime of every dollar. Look at the promised blessing! God wants your life to be full and overflowing not empty, overdrawn, overwhelmed, overbooked, and overcommitted.</p>
<p><strong>The Promise of Correction </strong><br />
Solomon goes on, “My son, do not despise the chastening of the Lord, nor detest His correction; For whom the Lord loves He corrects, just as a father the son in whom he delights. Happy is the man who finds wisdom…” (v. 11-13). When God disciplines His children, it is loving correction. The Heavenly father delights in you. He wants the best for you. God is a faithful Father. He loves us too much to let us get by with our sin. Hebrews 12 says, “Because the Lord disciplines the one he loves, and he chastens everyone he accepts as his son… If you are not disciplined…then you are not legitimate, not true sons and daughters at all” (v. 6, 8). Conviction can be painful, but confession and correction bring happiness. There are children I see in public, talking back to their parents. They are not honoring their parents or showing them respect. I want to correct them, but I can’t because they are not mine. There was a time I was headed in the wrong direction. I was not honoring the Lord with my time, tithe, or talent. But God in His mercy intervened and I made a course correction. I made a U-turn. He brought me to my senses. He got my life back on track. Praise God for His hand of correction on our lives!</p>
<p>True joy, fulfillment, and happiness is found in trusting Jesus. When you lean not on your own understanding, but trust and obey Him, you can be sure He’ll be right with you guiding you, providing for you, and correcting you along the path He has for you!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/01/26/blog-whyshoulditrustgod/">Why Should I Trust God? – Proverbs 3:5-13</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Does the Bible Say About Waiting on God? – Isaiah 40:27-31</title>
		<link>/2022/01/20/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutwaitingongod/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 14:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18744</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Isaiah 40:27 says, “Why do you say, O Jacob, and speak, O Israel: ‘My way is hidden from the Lord, and my just claim is passed over by my God’?” There are times when we think, God where are you? What are you doing? This is not fair! Do you ever feel passed over or...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/01/20/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutwaitingongod/">What Does the Bible Say About Waiting on God? – Isaiah 40:27-31</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Isaiah 40:27 says, “Why do you say, O Jacob, and speak, O Israel: ‘My way is hidden from the Lord, and my just claim is passed over by my God’?” There are times when we think, God where are you? What are you doing? This is not fair! Do you ever feel passed over or question why God is making you wait? Verses 29-30 say, “He gives power to the weak, and to those who have no might He increases strength. Even the youths shall faint and be weary, and the young men shall utterly fall….” Be encouraged today that God helps those who’ve come to the end of themselves. His power is made perfect in weakness (2 Cor. 12:9).</p>
<p>Why do we even get to the point where we ask God these questions? The point where we feel like maybe we’ve been ignored? According to this passage, the first reason is ignorance. Verse 28 says, “Have you not known? Have you not heard? The everlasting God, the Lord, the Creator of the ends of the earth, neither faints nor is weary. His understanding is unsearchable.” We have to get our eyes off of ourselves and on to Him. He never gets tired or weary. Notice the word “everlasting.” God has always been and always will be. He is the same yesterday, today, and forever! He was in all my yesterdays and He will be in all my tomorrows. He is not unsettled by clocks and calendars. He is never late and never early. He is the Creator of the ends of the earth. He is in charge all the time everywhere. His understanding is beyond us. God knows what He is doing even when we don’t understand what He is doing. While you are waiting God is working (Rom. 8:28).</p>
<p>The second reason seems to be inaction. Verse 31 says, “But those who wait on the Lord shall renew their strength….” Wait does not mean to do nothing. It means to trust, hope, expect. The same word is used in Psalm 27:14, “Wait on the Lord; be of good courage, and He shall strengthen your heart; Wait, I say, on the Lord!” Just because you were hoping, trusting, and expecting last year or 20 years ago, does not mean you are today. What are you doing today? Renew means to exchange. We lean hard on Jesus. He exchanges our weakness for His strength. “I can do all things through Christ who strengthens me” (Phil. 4:13).</p>
<p>What do we do while we wait? Cling to three promises found in verse 31, “…they shall mount up with wings like eagles, they shall run and not be weary, they shall walk and not faint.”</p>
<p><strong>Soar Above It– God Will Give You Visibility </strong><br />
God will enable you to see your wait from His viewpoint. He will give you His vision. One day in hindsight you will be able to understand the why behind the wait. In the meantime, God is doing something in you. If you take care of God’s business, God will take care of your business. There are plenty of examples in the Bible where people waited on the Lord. God’s delays are not His denials. God does something in you before He does something for you. The only thing worse than waiting is wishing you had. There is so much significance to the illustration of an eagle, but one thing about an eagle is that while most birds flee storms, the eagle seems to long for it because it enables him to soar higher than he can in normal conditions. At different times of our lives, we are all going to face storms. As we wait on the Lord and trust the Lord, He will not only take us through the storm, but He will actually lift us above the storm. God enables us to rise above it.</p>
<p><strong>Run to it – God Will Give You Vitality</strong><br />
“…They shall run and not be weary….” God will give you the energy you need. He’ll enable you to go further than you thought you could go. He will give you the ability to keep on going. God created the human body with adrenaline that releases in the emergency hours of life. You can do things you never thought you could do. When you are zapped of your strength, God will enable you to run. Run, not from God, but to Him.</p>
<p><strong>Walk Through It – God Will Give You the Victory</strong><br />
“…They shall walk and not faint.” It is harder to keep on walking than it is to fly or run. Walking is the daily grind. It is one thing to mount up with wings as eagles. It is one thing to run in the excitement.<br />
It is another to walk day after day. If you will wait on the Lord, He will give you the kind of staying power that will help you to keep walking when you don&#8217;t think you can take another step. Real victory is not in how fast you can run, but how far you can walk.</p>
<p>One of my favorite quotes by Charles Spurgeon says, “God is too wise to be mistaken. God is too good to be unkind. So when you don&#8217;t understand, when don&#8217;t see his plan, when you can&#8217;t trace His hand, trust His heart.” You can trust His heart today in your wait!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/01/20/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutwaitingongod/">What Does the Bible Say About Waiting on God? – Isaiah 40:27-31</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Are Some Keys to an Effective Prayer Life? – Acts 4</title>
		<link>/2022/01/11/blog-whataresomekeystoaneffectiveprayerlife/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 14:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week we started a new series on the Promises of God. We looked at 2 Peter 1:3-4, which says, “His divine power has given us everything we need for a godly life through our knowledge of him who called us by his own glory and goodness. Through these He has given us His very...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/01/11/blog-whataresomekeystoaneffectiveprayerlife/">What Are Some Keys to an Effective Prayer Life? – Acts 4</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week we started a new series on the Promises of God. We looked at 2 Peter 1:3-4, which says, “His divine power has given us everything we need for a godly life through our knowledge of him who called us by his own glory and goodness. Through these He has given us His very great and precious promises, so that through them you may participate in the divine nature, having escaped the corruption in the world caused by evil desires.” Notice the first part of this passage says that God has given us everything we need. Whatever we are going through, God has already provided. There are over 4,000 promises recorded in His word and a number of them pertain to prayer. As we look at the first and longest prayer recorded in Acts, we’ll see the four essentials of prayer and how God has given us all we need.</p>
<p><strong>The Name of God</strong><br />
In Acts 3, God used Peter and John to heal a man who had been lame from birth. When the people questioned them about it, they were quick to respond, “It is by the name of Jesus Christ of Nazareth, whom you crucified but whom God raised from the dead, that this man stands before you healed. Jesus is ‘the stone you builders rejected, which has become the cornerstone.’ Salvation is found in no one else, for there is no other name under heaven given to mankind by which we must be saved” (Acts 4:10-12). Prayer is all about a relationship with Jesus. You cannot get to God apart from Jesus. Jesus is the mediator between heaven and earth (1 Tim. 2:5). Jesus is our High Priest. Jesus is seated at the right hand of the Father and ever lives to make intercession for us (Heb. 7:25). Jesus came to seek and save the lost. There is salvation in no other name, but we have everything we need in the name of Jesus.</p>
<p><strong>The People of God</strong><br />
“On their release, Peter and John went back to their own people and reported all that the chief priests and the elders had said to them” (Acts 4:23). Their instinct was to get with God’s people and pray. When you are let go where do you go? The prayer promise in 2 Chronicles 7:14 begins, “If my people….” In Matthew 18, Jesus says that “if two of you on earth agree about anything they ask for, it will be done for them by my Father in heaven. For where two or three gather in my name, there am I with them” (v. 19-20). Gathering together with God’s people is so important!</p>
<p><strong>The Word of God</strong><br />
Notice also how they prayed. “When they heard this, they raised their voices together in prayer to God. ‘Sovereign Lord,’ they said, ‘you made the heavens and the earth and the sea, and everything in them. You spoke by the Holy Spirit through the mouth of your servant, our father David…” (Acts 4:24-25). They did not walk in silence, sit in silence, and one person pray and everyone else listen. They raised their voices and all prayed out loud. They prayed to the Sovereign Lord, getting their eyes off their problem and on their God. They also prayed scripture, what David had said in the Psalms. We pray to the Sovereign God who made everything and He can do anything. There is power when we pray scripture.</p>
<p><strong>The Spirit of God</strong><br />
In verse 29 we read that they prayed for boldness. Verse 31 tells us they were filled with the Holy Spirit and spoke the word of God boldly. They did not pray for persecution to stop but for boldness. They prayed for what they already had. Why? Because yesterday’s grace will not be enough for tomorrow’s challenges. As our days are so shall our strength/boldness be. They had also already received the Holy Spirit, but as believers we are to be continually filled, because we leak! “…‘Not by might nor by power, but by my Spirit,’ says the Lord Almighty” (Zech. 4:6). In Acts 2 the Holy Spirit came like a rushing mighty wind. You know when the wind is there and you know when it is not. You feel it. Even if your sail is up, you are not going anywhere without the wind. Even though you are working hard, you are not going anywhere without God’s Spirit. He is essential to spiritual success.</p>
<p>For Peter and John, prayer was their first response not their last resort. We should all learn to pray first, before we send the email, the text, leave the house, go to work, go to school. God has given us everything we need and He’s given us His precious promises we can cling to. Let’s pray the word of God, in the name of Jesus, with the people of God, through the power of the Spirit.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/01/11/blog-whataresomekeystoaneffectiveprayerlife/">What Are Some Keys to an Effective Prayer Life? – Acts 4</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Does the Bible Say About God’s Promises?</title>
		<link>/2022/01/06/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutgodspromises/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We all know what it is like to be on the receiving end of broken promises. When it happens enough, it can leave us jaded, cynical, or skeptical. People, in spite of their best intentions, will fail us. The Bible has a lot to say about the promises of God. Contrary to other people, He...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/01/06/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutgodspromises/">What Does the Bible Say About God’s Promises?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all know what it is like to be on the receiving end of broken promises. When it happens enough, it can leave us jaded, cynical, or skeptical. People, in spite of their best intentions, will fail us.</p>
<p>The Bible has a lot to say about the promises of God. Contrary to other people, He never breaks His promise to us. As we start a new series, I want you to:</p>
<p><strong>Discover God’s Promises</strong><br />
In 2 Peter 1:4, Peter refers to God’s promises as “precious.” He says that through them we may share in the divine nature. Too many Christians are controlled NOT by the heavenly nature but the earthly nature. We are more natural than supernatural. Do you look more like the culture or Christ? Your life, your choices, and your desires are either becoming more godly or evil. God’s promises enable us to escape the corruption that is in this world. People break their vows, but God cannot break His word (Heb. 6:17-19). His word is eternal and unchanging, just like His promises. You need to grab hold of God’s promises with both hands. Discover them. Look for them. Know them. David said in 1 Chronicles 17:19 that God has made known His great promises. The Bible is God’s promise book to you. Start reading your Bible every day looking for them.</p>
<p><strong>Discern God’s Promises</strong><br />
Not only should we discover God’s promises, but we should discern what they mean. God started making promises in the beginning. He made a promise to Adam and Eve in Genesis 3 that the seed of the woman would crush the Serpent’s head. That is why Jesus was born of a virgin, the seed of a woman. God made a promise to Abraham in Genesis 12 to bless him and that through him all the nations would be blessed. You may think, what do these promises have to do with me? Paul said, “The promises were spoken to Abraham and to his seed. Scripture does not say ‘and to seeds,’ meaning many people, but ‘and to your seed,’ meaning one person, who is Christ” (Gal. 3:16). The promises made to Adam and to Abraham all come to us through Christ. Think about God’s promise to David in 2 Samuel 7 that He would establish his throne forever. Acts 13:23 clarifies saying, “From this man’s descendants God has brought to Israel the Savior Jesus, as he promised.” Every one of God’s promises is “yes” in Christ (2 Cor. 1:20). Whatever the Father did for Jesus on earth He is able to do for us today. Whatever Jesus did for Paul He can do for us today.</p>
<p>Promises are unconditional on God’s part. He keeps His word. But promises are conditional on our part. We have to trust and obey. For example, Ephesians 6:2 tells us that the command to “Honor your father and mother” was the first command with promise. What does that mean? The promise is conditional on our obedience. If we honor our father and mother, the promise is that “days may be long in the land that the LORD your God is giving you” (Ex. 20:12). The promises of God require obedience and they require faith. Hebrew 11:6 says, “Now without faith it is impossible to please God, since the one who draws near to him must believe that he exists and that he rewards those who seek him.” We are going to start the new year seeking and believing God.</p>
<p><strong>Do God’s Promises</strong><br />
You have to look for God’s promises, learn God’s promises, and live God’s promises. David testified, “Your promises have been thoroughly tested, and your servant loves them” (Ps. 119:140). From the Old Testament to the New Testament, God promises “I will….” Salvation is one of His promises to all who believe. It is God who does the saving, God who does the sanctifying, we have to believe on the Lord Jesus. God has a purpose for your life and He will fulfill it. Whatever you need today, God has a promise for it. Find one you can cling to. I’m confident at the end of our lives, we’ll be able to say like Joshua, “Not one of all the Lord’s good promises to Israel failed; every one was fulfilled” (Josh. 21:45).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/01/06/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutgodspromises/">What Does the Bible Say About God’s Promises?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Can I Live At Peace With Those Around Me? – Romans 12</title>
		<link>/2021/12/26/blog-howcanileaveatpeacewiththosearoundme/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 14:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Peace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>During the holidays you are around people you seldom see. Sometimes that involves spending time with family, coworkers, and peers that given the choice, you may not pick to be with. Paul says, “If possible, as far as it depends on you, live at peace with everyone” (Rom. 12:18). Thankfully, throughout Romans 12, he tells...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/12/26/blog-howcanileaveatpeacewiththosearoundme/">How Can I Live At Peace With Those Around Me? – Romans 12</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During the holidays you are around people you seldom see. Sometimes that involves spending time with family, coworkers, and peers that given the choice, you may not pick to be with. Paul says, “If possible, as far as it depends on you, live at peace with everyone” (Rom. 12:18). Thankfully, throughout Romans 12, he tells us how.</p>
<p><strong>Transformation</strong><br />
In this chapter, Paul follows theology with application. The first thing he talks about is our relationship with God. Verses 1-3 say, “Therefore, brothers and sisters, in view of the mercies of God, I urge you to present your bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God; this is your true worship. Do not be conformed to this age, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind, so that you may discern what is the good, pleasing, and perfect will of God.” The first step to being at peace with everyone is to be at peace with God. Peace comes when you respond to the mercies of God. Mercy is God not giving us what we deserve. Your relationship with God is spiritual. It is based on Jesus’ sacrifice on the cross. In return, God asks for total sacrifice and total worship from us. Because He has shown us mercy, we can show mercy to others (1 Thess. 5:23). Peace is part of sanctification. The order given in 1 Thessalonians 5:23 is very important – spirit, soul, body. The reason people cannot find peace is because they try to start with the body (meds, drugs, alcohol). Peace comes from God himself. You have to start with the Spirit. Paul also tells us to be transformed by the renewing of our minds. If you want peace this Christmas, you have to win the battle of the mind (Is. 26:3). The battle you must win is the battle within!</p>
<p><strong>Appreciation</strong><br />
Paul continues in verses 3-6 talking about the body and different gifts. He refers to the church as a body and talks about our relationship with other believers. We are all different but are all one in Christ. Teeth chew, ears hear, eyes see, and feet walk, yet they are one body. The body has to work in harmony with itself. If the parts do not function together correctly, it becomes dysfunctional. Why are so many families and relationships dysfunctional? Because they do not appreciate one another’s differences. You see your differences as competing rather than completing. Romans 12:10 says we are to “love one another deeply as brothers and sister.” In your relationship with other believers, do you compete with one another or complete one another? Do you appreciate others or attack others?  </p>
<p><strong>Cooperation</strong><br />
Finally, Paul talks about our relationship with non-believers and our enemies. Verses 14-21 say, “Bless those who persecute you; bless and do not curse. Rejoice with those who rejoice; weep with those who weep. Live in harmony with one another. Do not be proud; instead, associate with the humble. Do not be wise in your own estimation. Do not repay anyone evil for evil. Give careful thought to do what is honorable in everyone’s eyes. If possible, as far as it depends on you, live at peace with everyone. Friends, do not avenge yourselves; instead, leave room for God’s wrath, because it is written, ‘Vengeance belongs to me; I will repay,’ says the Lord. Do not be conquered by evil, but conquer evil with good.” Don’t defend yourself. Let God do it and don’t get in His way. He can make even your enemies be at peace with you (Ps. 16:7). The devil is the great accuser. Accusations divide. Proverbs 19:11 says, “A person’s insight gives him patience, and his virtue is to overlook an offense.” Discretion makes you slow to anger. A person at war with themselves will be at war with everyone around them. Don’t take it personally. Sure, they offended you, but overlook it. It is a decision. Get over it. You have more important things to do this Christmas than live offended. Living offended is not going to help you or anyone else. Live at peace.  </p>
<p>People today are quick to be offended. You always find what you are looking for. If you are looking to be offended, you will be. You cannot control what happens to you, but you can control how you respond. It takes two to fight and two to reconcile but only one to forgive and only one to live in peace. We are not called to win arguments but to win souls. </p>
<p>Just like you wake up and get physically dressed every day, make sure your feet are fitted with the readiness that comes from the gospel of peace (Eph. 6:15). It will be hard, and you can’t do it on your own, but worry and anger don’t have to be normal. Peace should be normal for the believer. The most important relationship of all is your relationship with God. He is our Peace. When you have peace with Him, it affects everything else. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/12/26/blog-howcanileaveatpeacewiththosearoundme/">How Can I Live At Peace With Those Around Me? – Romans 12</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s Happening at Liberty in December 2021?</title>
		<link>/2021/12/15/blog-whats-happening-at-liberty-in-december-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 19:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Peace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>December is always such a full season. With its fullness comes many opportunities! There are three opportunities that we have the next couple of weeks that I don’t want you to miss: The Lord’s Supper – This Sunday in our services we will be taking the Lord’s Supper together. This will be the first time...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/12/15/blog-whats-happening-at-liberty-in-december-2021/">What&#8217;s Happening at Liberty in December 2021?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>December is always such a full season. With its fullness comes many opportunities! There are three opportunities that we have the next couple of weeks that I don’t want you to miss:</p>
<p><strong>The Lord’s Supper</strong> – This Sunday in our services we will be taking the Lord’s Supper together. This will be the first time we’ve done it on a Sunday morning since COVID. We have a special time planned to pause and remember Jesus’ sacrifice and all that He did for us on the cross.</p>
<p><strong>Christmas Eve Invite Cards</strong> – As I write this, there are only 8 days before our first Christmas Eve service. That means soon, our invite cards will be no good! Let’s make the most of this next week and invite, invite, invite. According to recent studies, more people will come to church at Christmas than any other time of year. We have such a unique opportunity right now to invite!</p>
<p><strong>Three Gifts for Jesus</strong> – Tammy and I started early in our parenting giving three gifts to each of our children. Just like Jesus received three gifts, every Christmas our children receive one “gold” gift, the big item, something they want; one “myrrh” gift, such as clothing or something they need; and one “frankincense” gift, like a Bible, devotional, book, or game. This December, I am asking you to prayerfully consider the following three gifts:</p>
<p>&#8211; <strong>Tithe</strong> – Look back over your income for 2021 and make sure you have given 10% to the church budget. Every dollar given covers 100% of the cost of doing ministry. God promises to bless our obedience when we give Him the first 10% of our income!</p>
<p>&#8211; <strong>The Big Give</strong> – Your gift to The Big Give this year goes towards Campus Development, Correctional Facility Ministries, and our School of Ministry. Our mission is changing lives, communities, and the world for Jesus Christ and each of these areas are unique avenues to carry out our God-given mission.</p>
<p>&#8211; <strong>International Missions Offering</strong> &#8211; The Lottie Moon Christmas Offering was established in 1988 to empower international missions efforts. Thousands of missionaries depend on this offering. Your giving enables missionaries to be sent to make disciples and multiply churches among unreached peoples and places for the glory of God. Every penny given goes to the mission field.</p>
<p><strong>Be intentional with Christmas this year.</strong> Make the most of this season and these opportunities. As you gather with friends and family, finish up your shopping, get the kids through their last week of school, remember Jesus. Make it a priority to be in church this Sunday. Ask God to give you opportunities to hand out invite cards and talk to others about the true meaning of the season. And don’t forget your gifts for Him.</p>
<p>Tammy and I love you and love celebrating Jesus with you!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/12/15/blog-whats-happening-at-liberty-in-december-2021/">What&#8217;s Happening at Liberty in December 2021?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Peace Possible?</title>
		<link>/2021/12/09/blog-ispeacepossible/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 21:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Peace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What a timely message we heard on Sunday! God moved! If you missed it, Daniel kicked off our series on Peace preaching on Isaiah 26:3, “You keep him in perfect peace whose mind is stayed on you, because he trusts in you.” You can watch here if you were not able to catch it on...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/12/09/blog-ispeacepossible/">Is Peace Possible?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What a timely message we heard on Sunday! God moved! If you missed it, Daniel kicked off our series on <em>Peace</em> preaching on Isaiah 26:3, “You keep him in perfect peace whose mind is stayed on you, because he trusts in you.” You can watch <a href="/messages/"><u>here</u></a> if you were not able to catch it on Sunday.</p>
<p>In a perfect world, the holiday season is “the most wonderful time of year.” We all know though that often the holidays can be stressful, sad, exhausting, grievous, and all things that seem opposite of “wonderful.” That is why I am so excited about our theme of <em>Peace.</em> Peace <em>is</em> possible during the holidays <em>and </em>throughout the rest of the year.</p>
<p>Another verse that echoes the message from Sunday is Romans 8:6. The NIV says, “The mind governed by the flesh is death, but the mind governed by the Spirit is life and peace.” The ESV says, “For to set the mind on the flesh is death, but to set the mind on the Spirit is life and peace.”</p>
<p>Every day we have to fight the battle for our minds. Like Daniel said, “Your mind is a battlefield for peace.” We have to keep our minds “stayed on,” “governed by,” and “set on” the Lord. While redirecting and renewing our minds is a daily, even sometimes hourly (or maybe even minute-ly, ha!) thing, gathering and worshipping together with other believers significantly helps as well.</p>
<p>There are three more Sundays in December. If you live near one of our campuses, I encourage you to make it a priority to be here each week. This coming Sunday, I will continue the <em>Peace</em> series and will also be interviewing a young lady who is leaving soon to serve as a missionary overseas for the next two years. December 19, we have a special service planned to include the Lord’s Supper. This will be the first time we’ve taken it on a Sunday morning together since the start of COVID. December 26 will be the last Sunday before the new year. Each campus has something a little different planned and I know it will be such a blessing to you.</p>
<p>We also have our Christmas Eve services that start on December 23. What a way to experience peace in the midst of chaos! Pause with your family and attend a service together. Set aside that hour to reflect on Jesus coming to earth, the Wonderful Counselor, Mighty God, and <em>Prince of Peace</em>. The services are at 6:30 p.m. on the 23<sup>rd</sup> and at 3:00 and 5:00 p.m. on the 24<sup>th</sup> at each location.</p>
<p>I’ve said it before and will most likely say it again, but Tammy and I are praying 2 Thessalonians 3:16 over you this season. Even now as I write this, I’m praying again, “Now may the Lord of peace Himself give you peace at all times and in every way. The Lord be with all of you.”</p>
<p>See you Sunday!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/12/09/blog-ispeacepossible/">Is Peace Possible?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Are Some Marks of Thanksgiving? – Jonah 2:1-3:1</title>
		<link>/2021/11/30/blog-marksofthanksgiving/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 15:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As I was preparing for our Thanksgiving series, I looked at all the passages in the Bible where “thanksgiving” is used. Jonah is one of the most popular stories in the Bible, but it is also one of the most controversial. Liberal theologians and skeptics have a hard time believing that a man could be...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/30/blog-marksofthanksgiving/">What Are Some Marks of Thanksgiving? – Jonah 2:1-3:1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I was preparing for our Thanksgiving series, I looked at all the passages in the Bible where “thanksgiving” is used. Jonah is one of the most popular stories in the Bible, but it is also one of the most controversial. Liberal theologians and skeptics have a hard time believing that a man could be swallowed by a great fish and live for three days and nights. It is important though that we believe the Bible by faith. If the Shipyard in Hampton Roads can engineer and build a nuclear submarine that can keep human beings alive for months under the ocean, don’t you think the Creator of the universe can? As we look closer at the story of Jonah, we will see three distinct marks of thanksgiving.</p>
<p><strong>Prayer</strong><br />
Jonah 2:1 begins, “Jonah prayed to the Lord his God….” Prayer shows our dependence on God. Thanksgiving to God is a sign that you have put your trust in God. Fear and doubt only show a lack of trust in God. Do you feel like you have been swallowed by a great fish? Like you are drowning? Like you are in a storm? Pride will keep you from praying. Don’t be too proud to call on God. You can’t make it on your own. Notice that Jonah prayed “to his God.” Jonah had gotten away from God. Fellowship was broken but Jonah was still God’s child and God was still his Father. You may have gotten far from God and even turned your back on God, but God has not turned his back on you. There are times when we all feel like God has forgotten us (see verses 4, 7). You may feel like God has passed you by. The same God who saw Jonah sees you! Jonah testified, “The water engulfed me up to the neck; the watery depths overcame me; seaweed was wrapped around my head. I sank to the foundations of the mountains, the earth’s gates shut behind me forever! Then you raised my life from the Pit, Lord my God!” (v. 5-6). Jonah thought it was all over, but it is not over until God says it is over! Maybe you feel down, discouraged, or depressed after the Thanksgiving holiday. Jonah had hit rock bottom. He was desperate. But God works through desperation. The way up is down on our knees. The first mark of thanksgiving is prayer.</p>
<p><strong>Purpose</strong><br />
Jonah continued, “Those who cherish worthless idols abandon their faithful love, but as for me, I will sacrifice to you with a voice of thanksgiving. I will fulfill what I have vowed. Salvation belongs to the Lord” (v. 8-9). God had Jonah positioned for a purpose. In chapter 1, he made excuses. Here am I Lord, send someone else… It is not a good time… I don’t even like those people… Why can’t I be a prophet to Israel like the other prophets? Do you ever compare yourself to others? Why can’t I…? Don’t let your feelings overcome you. Don’t let your feelings deceive you. Don’t let your feelings determine the will of God. In chapter 1 Jonah made excuses. In chapter 2, he had regrets. Today’s excuses will be tomorrow’s regrets! Life is a journey. Do you have regrets today? Don’t listen to the lies of the devil that your life is wasted. God has the final word! What got Jonah in trouble to begin with was believing a lie. Idol worship seems so primitive and third world, but every day we have idols and false gods that compete for the throne of our heart. We do our bowing to our bank accounts, credit cards, smart phones, search engines, and calendars. Idols are self-centered. They are for the worshipper not for God. Remember our purpose in life is to live for God not self. The purpose in receiving a blessing is to be a blessing. When we live out our purpose of magnifying Christ, we can’t help but praise and thank Him.</p>
<p><strong>Praise</strong><br />
“In everything give thanks: for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus concerning you” (1 Thess. 5:18). If Jonah could offer thanksgiving and praise from the belly of the great fish, then you can offer thanksgiving and praise in your present situation. Note, Jonah did not ask to be delivered but he started praising God and he was delivered. Praise is a weapon that overcomes. It’s amazing what praising can do! Praise the Lord. He can work through those who praise Him. Praise the Lord. For our God inhabits praise. Praise the Lord. For the chains that seem to bind you serve only to remind you that they drop powerless behind you when you praise Him. Jonah, Job, Paul, and Silas all sang a song of thanksgiving in the night. Praise is the key that unlocks prison doors and will set your free. You don’t have to praise God for what He has done but just start praising God for who He is. Don’t give in or give up, give thanks!</p>
<p>Jonah 3:1-2 says, “The word of the Lord came to Jonah a second time: ‘Get up! Go to the great city of Nineveh and preach the message that I tell you.” Only the perfect people – the pharisees, religious, legalists, did not need a second chance. The rest of us need a second chance. What past failures and regrets are keeping you from doing what God wants you to do? What is keeping you from living a life of thanksgiving? No one is beyond the grace of God. The Christian life is about new beginnings. God is the God of another chance. He is the God of new beginnings. Thank God today that He is the God of another chance. Spend time praying, remembering your purpose, and praising God for all that He is.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/30/blog-marksofthanksgiving/">What Are Some Marks of Thanksgiving? – Jonah 2:1-3:1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Can I Do if I Don’t Feel Thankful? – Isaiah 51:1-18</title>
		<link>/2021/11/22/blog-whatifidontfeelthankful/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 18:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Thanksgiving is only a few days away. There is always reason to be thankful. If you need a little encouragement this year, look at Isaiah 51. There are three things we can do to help us remember all that we have to be thankful for. Look Back at History “Listen to me, you who pursue...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/22/blog-whatifidontfeelthankful/">What Can I Do if I Don’t Feel Thankful? – Isaiah 51:1-18</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanksgiving is only a few days away. There is always reason to be thankful. If you need a little encouragement this year, look at Isaiah 51. There are three things we can do to help us remember all that we have to be thankful for.</p>
<p><strong>Look Back at History</strong><br />
“Listen to me, you who pursue righteousness, you who seek the Lord: Look to the rock from which you were cut, and to the quarry from which you were dug” (Is. 51:1). God dug us out of the pit of sin and set our feet on the Rock of Ages. Never forget where God brought you from. It will guard against an entitlement mindset. God does not owe me anything. Anything that is a notch above hell is better than I deserve. Remember your spiritual roots. Stay focused on the Word of God and on prayer. Remember the promises of God. Verse 2 says, “Look to Abraham your father, and to Sarah who gave birth to you. When I called him, he was only one; I blessed him and made him many.” Abraham left it all to follow God. He was blessed to be a blessing to the world, just like we are blessed to be a blessing. Abraham and Sarah’s journey was not easy, but God is a covenant keeping God. He will not break His promises! Take time to look back and remember where God has brought you from and you will be thankful!</p>
<p><strong>Look Up at Eternity</strong><br />
Look at the repeated words in verses 5-6: salvation, righteousness, forever. Jesus came to seek and save the lost. Everyone either spends eternity in a place called hell, separated from God, or in a place called heaven, in the presence of God. The One, who is our Creator, wants to be our Father. Verses 7-9 say, “Listen to me, you who know righteousness, the people in whose heart is my instruction: do not fear disgrace by men, and do not be shattered by their taunts. For moths will devour them like a garment, and worms will eat them like wool. But my righteousness will last forever, and my salvation for all generations. Wake up, wake up….” We need a spiritual awakening! We need to pass our faith on to the next generation. What you do for self and this world will pass away, but what we do for Jesus lasts forever! Look up and remember there is more to this life than this life. Get your eyes off earth and on eternity. Thank God for His salvation and His righteousness.</p>
<p><strong>Look Ahead at Destiny </strong><br />
“And the ransomed of the Lord will return and come to Zion with singing, crowned with unending joy. Joy and gladness will overtake them, and sorrow and sighing will flee” (v. 11). The context of Isaiah 51 is God preparing Israel to leave Babylon and come home. The God who brought Israel out of Egypt and out of Babylon will one day bring us out of this wilderness world of sin. Heaven is a place of joy, gladness, and no sorrow. Revelation 21:4 says, “He will wipe away every tear from their eyes. Death will be no more; grief, crying, and pain will be no more, because the previous things have passed away.” We can look to the future with gratitude rather than grief. The best is yet to come for the people of God!</p>
<p>How can I say thanks<br />
For the things You have done for me?<br />
Things so undeserved<br />
Yet You gave to prove Your love for me<br />
The voices of a million angels<br />
Could not express my gratitude<br />
All that I am and ever hope to be<br />
I owe it all to Thee<br />
To God be the glory<br />
To God be the glory<br />
To God be the glory<br />
For the things He has done<br />
With His blood He has saved me<br />
With His power He has raised me<br />
To God be the glory<br />
For the things He has done</p>
<p>Thanksgiving to God is a sign that you have put your trust in God. Worry, doubt, and fear only show a lack of trust in God. Trust in God’s future faithfulness is rooted in gratitude for God’s past faithfulness. What God has already done is a reminder for what He will do. Thanksgiving feeds trust. Think about where you have come from and where you are going, and you can’t help but be thankful.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/22/blog-whatifidontfeelthankful/">What Can I Do if I Don’t Feel Thankful? – Isaiah 51:1-18</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Do I Grow in Gratitude? – 2 Corinthians 8-9</title>
		<link>/2021/11/15/blog-howdoigrowingratitude/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 14:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>God is concerned with our thinking and our living. God wants us to have an attitude of gratitude. Second Corinthians 8-9 is the most extensive section on giving in all of Scripture. Here, Paul lays down basic principles of New Testament generosity. You may be thinking, how does giving affect gratitude? Paul says, “You will...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/15/blog-howdoigrowingratitude/">How Do I Grow in Gratitude? – 2 Corinthians 8-9</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>God is concerned with our thinking and our living. God wants us to have an attitude of gratitude. Second Corinthians 8-9 is the most extensive section on giving in all of Scripture. Here, Paul lays down basic principles of New Testament generosity. You may be thinking, how does giving affect gratitude? Paul says, “You will be enriched in every way for all generosity, which produces thanksgiving to God through us” (2 Cor. 9:11). There are nine different words used to refer to this offering they are taking up, but the one used the most was grace. We know we are growing in grace and gratitude when we give:</p>
<p><strong>Personally</strong><br />
Speaking of the way the churches in Macedonia gave, Paul says, “…they gave themselves first to the Lord and then to us by God’s will” (2 Cor. 8:5). God does not need or want our money. He wants our life! God wants something FOR us not FROM us! When we give, we are not giving to a project, we are giving to a person. Jesus says, “Do it for me” (see Matt. 25:31-40).</p>
<p><strong>Sacrificially</strong><br />
“For you know the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ: Though he was rich, for your sake he became poor, so that by his poverty you might become rich” (2 Cor. 8:9). Jesus said, “For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also” (Mt. 6:21). He is not after your treasure. He is after your heart. He knows your money’s direction reveals your heart’s affection. Our world is caught up in the “consumption assumption.” We spend on newer, nicer upgrades and extra stuff, then we pay debt, then we save, and if we have anything left we give. That formula is ME, ME, ME, and then God or others. What is sacrificial living? It is living a self-less life instead of a selfish life. Jesus flipped that script. He said, “But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be provided for you” (Mt. 6:33). The things you worry about, God will take care of! We have to give, then save, then spend. Present yourself a living sacrifice which is pleasing to God. You give to what you love. You sacrifice for your children or for something you really want. Giving is a tangible way we express our love for Jesus. Why do we give? Because of all Jesus has given to us.</p>
<p><strong>Cheerfully</strong><br />
“Each person should do as he has decided in his heart—not reluctantly or out of compulsion, since God loves a cheerful giver” (2 Cor. 9:7). God loves cheerful giving, but He hates stinginess because God hates sin. How do we become cheerful givers? Practice makes perfect. Give not out of pressure but out of pleasure. There is no joy like doing something for others. Give not out of obligation but out of opportunity. It is not that you have to, but you get to. Giving is not a job it is a joy! When I think about how the Lord saved me, came to me when I could not come to Him, forgave all my sins, cast them as far as the east is from the west, turned my life around, gave me a reason and a purpose for living, placed my feet on the solid rock, gave me the promise of the resurrection and heaven, it makes me want to give! We give with the attitude, Thank you, Lord!</p>
<p><strong>Generously</strong><br />
Those in Macedonia gave in spite of their circumstances (2 Cor. 8:1-4). They did not let their circumstances hinder them. They could have easily made excuses. You can make excuses, or you can make progress, but you can&#8217;t do both. In spite of Covid, inflation, gas prices, and more, we can give. In the economy of God, poverty and generosity co-exist. Severe trial and abundant joy co-exist. Man looks at how much we give. God looks at how much we have left over. They gave out of their extreme poverty. Generosity is not something that happens when you make it big. It is about being generous right now with what we have. These people begged to be a part of the offering. It was voluntary, spontaneous, not because they had to but because they wanted to participate! That is what the grace of God does in us. We are all born with a clinched fist. But the grace of God causes us to live with an open hand and open heart. “The point is this: The person who sows sparingly will also reap sparingly, and the person who sows generously will also reap generously” (2 Cor. 9:6). If you were God, would you give more to those who are generous or more to those who are stingy? You can’t reap what you do not sow. Generosity is not something we do, it is a way of life. The more we invest in God’s Kingdom the more fruit will abound. The greater the investment the greater the return. “And God is able to make every grace overflow to you, so that in every way, always having everything you need, you may excel in every good work” (2 Cor. 9:8).</p>
<p>What a promise! God is able when we are not able. “You will be enriched in every way for all generosity, which produces thanksgiving to God through us. For the ministry of this service is not only supplying the needs of the saints but is also overflowing in many expressions of thanks to God” (2 Cor. 9:11-12). How do we grow in thanksgiving? Never get used to your blessings or take them for granted. Remember the best blessings are spiritual and money cannot buy them. Share your blessings. What is the more for? God blesses us so that we may be a blessing to others. When we give to the Lord’s work, only God gets the glory!</p>
<ol>
<li>Adapted from <em>If Money Talked</em> by Andy Stanley</li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/15/blog-howdoigrowingratitude/">How Do I Grow in Gratitude? – 2 Corinthians 8-9</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Do I Overcome Depression?</title>
		<link>/2021/11/15/blog-overcomingdepression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 14:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Overcoming Depression]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Everyone gets discouraged, depressed, anxious, and fearful. Worry is a thief. It steals your joy. No one wants to live this way, but at times we all do. So how do we overcome? The Sickness of Depression Depression is not a sin but a sickness. It is not a sin to be sick. Depression is...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/15/blog-overcomingdepression/">How Do I Overcome Depression?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everyone gets discouraged, depressed, anxious, and fearful. Worry is a thief. It steals your joy. No one wants to live this way, but at times we all do. So how do we overcome?</p>
<p><strong>The Sickness of Depression</strong><br />
Depression is not a sin but a sickness. It is not a sin to be sick. Depression is the world’s number one health problem causing more deaths than cancer each year. It is a feeling of helplessness and hopelessness that leads to intense sadness. It is a fallacy to think that if you love God, you will never be depressed. That would be like saying if you love God, you will never have headaches, backaches, heart attacks, allergies, arthritis, bronchitis, pneumonia, or high cholesterol. Some of the greatest people who ever lived battled depression – Abraham Lincoln, Winston Churchill, and Charles Hadden Spurgeon to name a few. First Peter 4:12 says, “Beloved, do not think it strange concerning the fiery trial which is to try you, as though some strange thing happened to you.” Everyone sooner or later will experience depression to one degree or another. Someone called it “the common cold of our emotions.” It is a common experience because we are all human. First Corinthians 10:13 says, “No temptation has come upon you except what is common to humanity….” If you experience depression, you are not alone! We have to be honest and admit we are not superman but we are human! Did you know that Moses, Jonah, and Elijah were so depressed that they all prayed to die (Num. 11:14-15, Jon. 4:8, 1 Kin. 19:1-4)? The devil does not fight fair. 1 Peter 5:9 says, “Resist him, steadfast in the faith, knowing that the same sufferings are experienced by your brotherhood in the world.”</p>
<p><strong>The Symptoms of Depression</strong><br />
In the cases of Moses, Jonah, and Elijah their depression came on the hills of success. Moses the Exodus, Jonah the city-wide revival, and Elijah saw fire fall from heaven. Depression will sometimes hit you when everything is going well. You have everything anyone would want in life but you feel so empty inside. You are running so fast you are running on empty. What goes up must come down. Life is filled with highs and lows. Elijah went from hero to zero. Sometimes it hits when you have experienced some great loss: health, divorce, or the death of a loved one. Depression can cause you to feel like you don’t want to get out of the bed. You may feel sad, empty, hopeless, angry, or irritable, even over small matters. You may lose interest in normal activities or suffer from insomnia or sleeping too much. Some have a reduced appetite and others an increased appetite. You may have trouble thinking or concentrating. Certainly with Moses, Jonah, and Elijah they were overloaded and overwhelmed. They were physically exhausted (their bodies were affected). Sometimes you may be emotionally exhausted (your soul is affected). Sometimes there is a chemical imbalance, but sometimes it is a calendar imbalance. Go to the doctor. Seek professional help. Start eating healthy. Take your medication. Trim your calendar. Learn to say, “No.” We are made in the image of God, who is a triune being. The body is physical. The soul is mental and emotional. The spirit is spiritual. It’s possible to be spiritually exhausted as well. We are in a spiritual battle. The enemy comes to steal, kill, and destroy. Jesus came to give us life! It is ok to not be ok. There should be no stigma to being sick physically or mentally. Whatever your illness, it is not your identity. There is hope!</p>
<p><strong>The Survival of Depression </strong><br />
Don’t give in or give up. You are going to make it! The devil wants you to have a breakdown. God wants you to have a breakthrough! God gave Moses help because he was working night and day (Num. 11:14-17). If you try to be everything to everyone you will probably not be worth anything to anyone! We need to eliminate and delegate. God gave Elijah some R&amp;R (1 Kin. 19:5-8) and a project and a partner (v. 9-17). Everyone needs to do some type of meaningful work, to do something that matters. Everyone needs a community of friends who loves them unconditionally. Everyone needs to take whatever suffering and pain they have experienced and let God use it for good. There is purpose in the pain. “Ultimately, your pain is either a jail that imprisons you or a school that empowers you.”</p>
<p>Elijah had an encounter with God. Hear His still small voice speaking to you today. The second part of 1 Corinthians 10:13 that we looked at above says, “But God is faithful; he will not allow you to be tempted beyond what you are able, but with the temptation he will also provide the way out so that you may be able to bear it.” God can heal you instantly but more times than not it is a process. God can heal you or He will enable you to live with your issue and be a survivor. Dr. Ron Dunn was one of the greatest Bible teachers of our day, but he battled depression. His son battled depression and committed suicide. I heard him say one time, “The question is not do I have enough faith to be healed. The question is do I have enough faith to say sick?” Ask yourself today, “What if God does not heal me in this life?” I’m here to tell you, you can make it! God will give you what you need to bear it and get through it. Ultimate healing is in heaven. You can survive and thrive. Your greatest ministry always comes out of your greatest pain. Sometimes you have to find yourself in a dark place to appreciate the light. Elijah and Moses went on to be at the transfiguration of Jesus. Jesus used Jonah as a sign of his resurrection. They overcame and you can too!</p>
<p>https://www.healthline.com/health/depression/facts-statistics-infographic#7</p>
<p>https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/depression/symptoms-causes/syc-20356007</p>
<p>Out of the Cave by Chris Hodges, Pg 193.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/15/blog-overcomingdepression/">How Do I Overcome Depression?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Does the Bible Say About Relationships?</title>
		<link>/2021/11/02/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutrelationships/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 17:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What makes us most happy in life? It is not more money, success, or achievements. No. It is relationships. Happiness was made to be shared. God never intended us to live life alone. We all long to belong because God made us that way. Healthy relationships make us happy and unhealthy relationships can make us...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/02/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutrelationships/">What Does the Bible Say About Relationships?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What makes us most happy in life? It is not more money, success, or achievements. No. It is relationships. Happiness was made to be shared. God never intended us to live life alone. We all long to belong because God made us that way. Healthy relationships make us happy and unhealthy relationships can make us miserable. From the Old Testament to the New Testament, the Bible is a book about relationships.</p>
<p><strong>Family Relationships</strong><br />
Mark and Barnabas were cousins. In Acts 23 it was Paul’s nephew who warned him of the plot to kill him. In the Gospels we learn that many of the disciples were family. The story of the Old Testament is about a man named Abraham, his son Isaac, and grandson Jacob, and his descendants. The story of the Exodus is about Moses and his brother Aaron and his sister Miriam. You get the picture. God created you in His image, and put you in a family. You may have been raised by a single parent, grandparents, step-parents, or in a blended family. God puts us in families and relationships that start at home. Your early relationships affect all your other relationships in life. There are no perfect families, despite what we see on social media. Respect is the core of family relationships. Your relationships can only be as healthy as you are, and no other relationship shapes who you are more than family. What you think, feel, say, and do has to do with the home you grew up in. Family is where we learn to trust or distrust. It is where we learn to be quiet or speak up. Where we learn to hide our emotions or share our feelings. What role did you play in your family growing up? We are all homeschooled whether we know it or not. The home is the university of relationships.</p>
<p><strong>Friend Relationships</strong><br />
Over 10 names are mentioned in Colossians 4, and it follows the pattern we see at the end of Paul’s letters. At the end of the book of Romans, Paul mentions more than 30 names! Paul traveled with friends; he stayed with friends; he visited friend; worked alongside friends; preached alongside friends; he was beaten alongside friends. He sang in prison with his friends. He encouraged his friends and was encouraged by his friends. There were times he disagreed with his friends and times he was reconciled with his friends. Mark is an example. God said it is not good to be alone. Studies show that friends help to ward off depression, boost our immune system, lower cholesterol, increase the odds of surviving a heart attack and extend your life expectancy. We have friends for a reason (something in common), friends for a season (a chapter of life), and friends of treason (they betray or fail you). Friendships that are there for one season and not the next are not failed friendships. Thank God for the joy they brought you on the journey during that time. Remember the best and forget the rest. You know the old saying, “You don’t get to choose your family, but you do get to choose your friends.” Proverbs 12:26 says, “The righteous should choose his friends carefully, For the way of the wicked leads them astray.” Show me your friends and I will show you your future! Friends are like buttons on an elevator. They either take you up or they take you down! A real friend walks in when everyone else walks out. You only have so much time and energy to give. It is one thing to start a friendship it is another to maintain it. It is so easy to take friends for granted. Good friends keep their word. They keep their promises. They don’t abandon you. Friends disappoint you and you disappoint your friends. The friends we keep the longest are the friends we keep forgiving.</p>
<p><strong>Forever Relationships </strong><br />
You were not born knowing God, but He knew you. He knew you when you were in your mother’s womb (Jer. 1:5, Ps. 139:14). The ultimate goal in life is a loving relationship with the one who created you. The most important relationship you will have in life is your relationship with God. Your relationship with God will affect all of your other relationships. Life begins and ends with God. The greatest need of the children born into our families is to be born again into God’s family. Relationships can be complicated! We have to remember that our significance is found in God. He loves you like you are the only one on earth. If God had a refrigerator your picture would be on it! Through Him we can be the friend, spouse, parent, or employee He’s called us to be. Through Him we can forgive when we’ve been wronged. Through Him we can heal from past hurts. And ultimately, through Him, we have a relationship that will last forever!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/11/02/blog-whatdoesthebiblesayaboutrelationships/">What Does the Bible Say About Relationships?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Can We Finish October Strong?</title>
		<link>/2021/10/25/blog-finishoctoberstrong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 13:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Colossians]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Can you believe it is the last week of October already? I feel like summer just started and now Christmas is only 8 weeks away! I tell you this for a couple of reasons: First, THIS WEEK is a week of big opportunity! 757 Strong – Our 757 Strong emphasis is happening NOW. This is...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/25/blog-finishoctoberstrong/">How Can We Finish October Strong?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can you believe it is the last week of October already? I feel like summer just started and now Christmas is only 8 weeks away! I tell you this for a couple of reasons:</p>
<p>First, <strong>THIS WEEK</strong> is a week of big opportunity!</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>757 Strong</strong> – Our 757 Strong emphasis is happening <strong>NOW</strong>. This is a week where the Liberty family focuses on loving and serving our community. If you haven’t already, <strong>I invite you to serve with us!</strong> We’ve posted a list of needs at <a href="http://www.libertylive.church/757strong">libertylive.church/757strong</a>, or you can simply meet a need that you notice around you. Little things go a long way! You can sign up as an individual or a group and find a tangible way to show God’s love to our community.</li>
<li><strong>North Africa Mission Trip</strong> – This Friday we have a team leaving to serve in North Africa. They will be giving school supplies to kids who need them in order to attend school. The goal is to share the gospel. Remember, our mission is to change lives, communities, and <strong>the world</strong> for Jesus Christ!</li>
<li><strong>Candy-Palooza</strong> – This Sunday, Liberty Kids is hosting Candy-Palooza! Kids can come in their costume (nothing scary, please) for a time of games, prizes, and lots of candy. If you know any kids, invite them! They will love it and most importantly, they will have a chance to hear the gospel. Why not take a secular holiday and use it for the glory of God?!</li>
<li><strong>Halloween</strong> – This Sunday is also Halloween. There is no other time during the year that all your neighbors come to you. Don’t forget to grab a stack of Liberty invite cards and some GOOD candy to hand out. Again, let’s use the opportunity for the glory of God! Tammy and I love sitting in the driveway handing out candy at Halloween. Every kid that comes by gets a Liberty invite card and we have a great time!</li>
</ul>
<p>Please be praying for each of these opportunities. Pray that God would show you how you can share the gospel this week. Pray that people would be open and receptive. And pray that lives would be forever changed.</p>
<p>Another reason I remind you that Christmas is so close, is because we have <strong>two great gift options</strong> that will be available soon. Every year I participate in a devotional project with 51 other pastors and church leaders. We each write a week of devotions and they are combined in a nice leather-bound book. These <strong>devotionals are great gifts!</strong> They are only <strong>$20</strong> and they are gifts that keep on giving all year.</p>
<p>The second option is <strong>a new book called <em>Goodbye Fear</em>.</strong> If you remember at the beginning of the year, I preached a sermon series on fear. God used that series as such an encouragement to me! From that series, I wrote a book that comes out next month. It is only <strong>$4.99</strong> and will also be a great gift! All of us face fear at some point or another, but God has told us over and over that we do not have to fear because He is with us.</p>
<p>Both books will be available soon online and at each of our campuses. We’ve been hearing on the news that Christmas gifts will be hard to come by, so I wanted to let you know early that these are coming.</p>
<p>I hope you have a great week! I can’t wait to hear stories of all God does!</p>
<p>It is a joy to be your Pastor!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/25/blog-finishoctoberstrong/">How Can We Finish October Strong?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Can I Be a Good Teammate for the Gospel? – Colossians 4:7-15</title>
		<link>/2021/10/21/blog-teammateforthegospel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 15:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Colossians]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Teamwork is powerful! Teams build ships, launch rockets, educate students, perform life-saving surgeries, and win championships! Teams face all kinds of adversity, challenges, and tests, but together they overcome. Teamwork unifies, identifies, solidifies, multiplies, and magnifies. Mother Teresa said, “you can do what I cannot do. I can do what you cannot do. Together, we...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/21/blog-teammateforthegospel/">How Can I Be a Good Teammate for the Gospel? – Colossians 4:7-15</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Teamwork is powerful! Teams build ships, launch rockets, educate students, perform life-saving surgeries, and win championships! Teams face all kinds of adversity, challenges, and tests, but together they overcome. Teamwork unifies, identifies, solidifies, multiplies, and magnifies. Mother Teresa said, “you can do what I cannot do. I can do what you cannot do. Together, we can do great things!”</p>
<p>In Colossians 4, we read a list of names. It’s like a group photo of Paul and his teammates. There are three characteristics that stand out. When we exude these characteristics and surround ourselves with others who do likewise, we can accomplish much for the glory of God.</p>
<p><strong>Faithfulness</strong><br />
In verses 7-10 we read about Tychicus, Onesimus, and Aristarchus. Paul refers to Tychicus as a dear brother in the Lord. He was faithful and he was a servant. Whether the task was big or small Paul knew he would get it done. Tychicus helped Paul deliver the offering from the Gentile churches to the poor saints in Jerusalem. He ministered to Paul and with Paul. Tychicus is mentioned in Acts 20, Ephesians 6, Colossians 4, 2 Timothy 4, and Titus 3. Onesimus was a runaway slave that Paul won to Christ. He and Tychicus delivered the book of Philemon. Paul trusted these men to speak on his behalf. They understood Paul’s heartbeat and were able to share the what and why of the vision God had given Paul. Aristarchus (who we read about in Acts 19, 20, and 27) was by Paul’s side in a riot in Ephesus, with him during the storm and shipwreck going to Rome, and here in jail by choice for the gospel to help Paul. He was a friend through the good times and the bad. Paul could not accomplish the work without his friends and partners in the ministry. They served behind the scenes with faithfulness. What do people say when they say your name? A dear brother? A servant? Faithful?</p>
<p><strong>Forgiveness</strong><br />
In verse 10 we also read about Mark. When no one else would have anything to do with Paul, Barnabas took him in and gave him a chance. In Acts 13 they went on their first missionary journey and took Mark as their assistant. But when persecution and adversity came, Mark abandoned them and returned home. Later, Paul and Barnabas planned to go on a second missionary journey, but they disagreed over taking Mark. Paul refused to give Mark a second chance, but God sided with Barnabas and Mark. God did not think Mark was finished. If God saw him qualified to write one of the four Gospels, don’t you think he was probably qualified to go on a short-term mission trip? You can disagree without being disagreeable! These men are men of God, yet they disagree. Good and godly people often come to different conclusions. Conflict is inevitable in this life. We are not going to see eye to eye on everything, but we should never let that stop us from doing the work of God. In this case, Paul and Barnabas left with grace and no bridges were burned. As we see in this passage, years later they are serving together again. It is a story of forgiveness and restoration. In Paul’s last book, 2 Timothy, he wrote that Mark was “helpful to me in my ministry” (2 Tim. 4:11). What an encouragement to all of us! We all fail and make mistakes. God can even use your failures to help others succeed.</p>
<p><strong>Fruitfulness</strong><br />
As we read on, we see that the ministry was multiplied through other people to other places. In verse 11 we see that Justus was with Paul. Sometimes all you need to do is just be there. You don’t have to know what to say. Just be there. He was not in the spotlight. All we know is that he was a co-worker and a comfort to Paul. The Lord knew his name. You may never get your name in print on earth but if you know Jesus, your name is written in heaven! Epaphras is mentioned in verse 12. He prayed constantly, personally, and specifically. He is mentioned three times in the New Testament. He was in the church and for the church. Luke is mentioned in verse 14. Luke is a Gentile. He wrote the Gospel of Luke and the book of Acts. He used his profession for the gospel. Your job is more than a job! Use your job for Jesus! Is what you are doing with your life going to show up in eternity? Nympha is mentioned in verse 15. We know nothing about her except she used her house for Jesus. We can all use what we have for the cause of Christ.</p>
<p>The remaining person in this passage is Demas (v. 14). No description is given of him like it was of the others. Many who begin well do not end well. Demas is mentioned three times in the New Testament (Philemon 2, Colossians 4, and 2 Timothy 4). Paul said in 2 Timothy 4:9, “…Demas has deserted me, since he loved this present world….” Worldliness is anything that excludes God. It is any activity or attitude that keeps you from loving God. Mark deserted Paul but he came back. Demas deserted and was never restored as far as we know. It hurt Paul deeply when Demas forsook and abandoned him. But it hurt Demas most of all. Choices have consequences. Are you living for this world or the world to come? Are you faithful, forgiving, and fruitful?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/21/blog-teammateforthegospel/">How Can I Be a Good Teammate for the Gospel? – Colossians 4:7-15</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Does It Mean to Be Devoted to Prayer? – Colossians 4:2-6</title>
		<link>/2021/10/14/blog-devotedtoprayer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 18:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Colossians]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of Colossians 4, Paul is instructing us on how to talk to God about people and how to talk to people about God. We do not have a more important ministry than our prayer ministry. All other ministries are powerless apart from prayer! You have heard it said, “When you sing you...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/14/blog-devotedtoprayer/">What Does It Mean to Be Devoted to Prayer? – Colossians 4:2-6</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of Colossians 4, Paul is instructing us on how to talk to God about people and how to talk to people about God. We do not have a more important ministry than our prayer ministry. All other ministries are powerless apart from prayer! You have heard it said, “When you sing you get what singing can do. When you preach you get what preaching can do. When you teach you get what teaching can do. But when you pray you get what God can do!” Colossians 4:2 begins, “Devote yourselves to prayer….” Being devoted means wholeheartedly, not half-hearted. It means to continually and steadfastly pray without ceasing. We need more than a prayer list we need a prayer life! We must take prayer seriously and not casually. Paul gives us four marks of devoted prayer.</p>
<p><strong>Watchful</strong><br />
“Devote yourselves to prayer; stay alert…” (v. 2). We wrestle not against flesh and blood. We must win the war spiritually. Do you know who are the devoted and alert prayer warriors? Parents who have a son or daughter in the military or warzone. Peter also gave the instruction to stay alert in 1 Peter 4:7. And 1 Peter 5:8-9 he says, “Be sober-minded, be alert. Your adversary the devil is prowling around like a roaring lion, looking for anyone he can devour. Resist him, firm in the faith, knowing that the same kind of sufferings are being experienced by your fellow believers throughout the world.” All believers have the same struggles. We are tempted by the world around us, the flesh within us, and the devil who is against us. Jesus said in Matthew 26:41, “Watch and pray, lest you enter into temptation. The spirit indeed is willing, but the flesh is weak.” You cannot watch without praying and you cannot pray without watching.</p>
<p><strong>Thankful</strong><br />
“Devote yourselves to prayer; stay alert in it with thanksgiving” (v. 2). Don’t ask for more until you thank God for what you have. Have an attitude of gratitude. Start and end your day with thanksgiving. Give thanks before every meal. Say “thank you” to people. Psalm 100 says, “Enter into His gates with thanksgiving, and into His courts with praise. Be thankful to Him, and bless His name. For the Lord is good; His mercy is everlasting, and His truth endures to all generations” (v. 4-5). First Thessalonians 5:18 says, “In everything give thanks; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.” You might be saying, “I feel like a hypocrite giving thanks when I don’t feel like it.” We do not live the Christian life on feelings but on faith. If we obey God, the sincerity and feelings will follow. We walk by faith and not by sight. It does not say thank God for all things but in all things.</p>
<p><strong>Purposeful</strong><br />
In verses 3-5, Paul asks the Colossians to pray for an open door to share Christ. He also admonishes them to act wisely toward outsiders. Someone said, “The purpose of prayer is not to get man’s will done in heaven but to get God’s will done on earth.” Prayer is not telling God what to do. It is asking God to do what He desires to do and only He can do. God is the God of the open door. He opens doors no man can shut and shuts doors no man can open. Paul did not ask them to pray him out of prison like I would have! Paul asked for doors of ministry to be opened. He prayed for God to use his imprisonment. There are only two kids of people in the world. Those in Christ and those outside Christ. We are all born outsiders. How do you turn outsiders into insiders? Let your light shine. Pray for open doors, open hearts, and open eyes. Act wisely. We are here for those who are not yet here. Are you making the most of the opportunities God gives you?</p>
<p><strong>Graceful</strong><br />
“Let your speech always be gracious, seasoned with salt, so that you may know how you should answer each person.” Our world desperately needs to see Christians who are civil. Speak the truth in love. It is embarrassing how some Christians and some pastors speak on social media. Our speech is to minister grace to the hearer. The world does not care how much you know until they know how much you care. It is possible to win an argument and lose a soul.</p>
<p>Prayer is the difference between what you and I can do and what God can do. If we want to accomplish things of eternal value and live a victorious Christian life, we must be people devoted to prayer.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/14/blog-devotedtoprayer/">What Does It Mean to Be Devoted to Prayer? – Colossians 4:2-6</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Can I Honor God in My Relationships? – Colossians 3:18-4:1</title>
		<link>/2021/10/12/blog-howcanihonorgodinmyrelationships/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 14:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Colossians]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We were made in the image of God for the purpose of serving Him. While there are a variety of ways we can do that, one way is through relationships. We have an opportunity every day to serve the Lord through how we interact with one another. Husbands and Wives As we pick up in...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/12/blog-howcanihonorgodinmyrelationships/">How Can I Honor God in My Relationships? – Colossians 3:18-4:1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We were made in the image of God for the purpose of serving Him. While there are a variety of ways we can do that, one way is through relationships. We have an opportunity every day to serve the Lord through how we interact with one another.</p>
<p><strong>Husbands and Wives</strong><br />
As we pick up in our study of Colossians, Paul says, “Wives, submit yourselves to your husbands, as is fitting in the Lord. Husbands, love your wives and don’t be bitter toward them” (Col. 3:18-19). In a day of self-expression and independence, submission is not a popular word; but Christians are not called to be politically correct. We are called to be Spirit-filled and to submit to one another (Eph. 5:21). God is a God of order. In 1 Corinthians 11:3, Paul speaks of the Godhead saying, “God is the head of Christ.” Christ is no second-class citizen and women are not second-class citizens. Christ is equally God as much as the Father is God. He is not inferior on any level. The Trinity is the model for all relationships. Jesus is the head of the Church, but He does not force the Church to do anything. Both Christ and the Father are equally God. Both the man and woman are created in the image of God (Gen 1:27). A wise husband needs the input of his wife. This does not mean they cannot disagree. But the husband is ultimately responsible for the decision. A wife’s submission is not absolute. It has limits. Notice the verse says, “as is fitting in the Lord.” A wife’s ultimate allegiance is to Jesus. If your husband asks you to do something that would be disobeying the Lord or puts your family in danger, submit to God not man. Husbands are to love their wives with a sacrificial love. What destroys homes and marriages is pride and selfishness. If the husband is submitted to the Lord and the wife is submitted to the Lord, they will have no problem submitting to one another. Anything with two heads is a freak and anything without a head is dead. Every business needs a CEO and every football team needs a quarterback. It has nothing to do with being superior or inferior. We all have different gifts, strengths, and different roles. The home is built on love and respect. The husband submits by showing his wife love. She submits by showing him respect. And in doing so, God is honored.</p>
<p><strong>Parents and Children</strong><br />
Paul continues, “Children, obey your parents in everything, for this pleases the Lord” (v. 20). Our culture is disintegrating because the family is disintegrating. Years ago, parents had lots of kids. Today, kids have lots of parents. Ephesians 6:2-3 says, “‘Honor your father and mother,’ which is the first commandment with promise: ‘that it may be well with you and you may live long on the earth.’” Obedience has to do with actions. Honor is an attitude. Obeying is temporary. Honor is lasting. Children obey when they are young, the goal being for a child to obey God. Children can honor their parents all their life by talking to them, seeking advice, but doing what God calls you to do. “Fathers, do not exasperate your children, so that they won’t become discouraged” (v. 21). Don’t correct your kids in a way that embitters them. God disciplines those He loves (Prov. 3:12). Some parents are too authoritarian and do not exercise love. Others are too permissive and do not exercise discipline. A good rule of thumb is to have A – Authority over their attitude and actions, B – Boundaries for their behavior, and C – Consequences with consistency.</p>
<p><strong>Employers and Employees </strong><br />
“Slaves, obey your human masters in everything. Don’t work only while being watched, as people-pleasers, but work wholeheartedly, fearing the Lord. Whatever you do, do it from the heart, as something done for the Lord and not for people, knowing that you will receive the reward of an inheritance from the Lord. You serve the Lord Christ. For the wrongdoer will be paid back for whatever wrong he has done, and there is no favoritism. Masters, deal with your slaves justly and fairly, since you know that you too have a Master in heaven” (Col. 3:22-4:1). Paul is in no way condoning what we in the Western world think of when we say, “slavery.” In Exodus 21:16 human beings were not to be kidnapped or sold. In Exodus 21:26 slaves were not to be abused. Paul is referring to indentured servanthood, a voluntary contract that didn’t last for a lifetime and was not based on race. These principles in our day apply to the employee/employer relationship. This is what it looks like to be a Christian at work. God is your real boss. You don’t work for “them” you work for “Him.” Serve the Lord in your job. Never just do the minimum required. Always do your best. God is watching and He will reward you. Excellence is not perfection. If you are an employer, treat your employees with dignity, justness, and fairness.</p>
<p>If you are struggling in one or more of these relationships it may be because the number one relationship in your life is not right. Submit to God today. Ask Jesus to take control of your life, home, family, work. Submit by confessing Jesus Christ is Lord. We all fall short. That is why we need Jesus. There are no perfect marriages, parents, kids, workplaces. But we do have a perfect Jesus!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/12/blog-howcanihonorgodinmyrelationships/">How Can I Honor God in My Relationships? – Colossians 3:18-4:1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>October 2021 Updates</title>
		<link>/2021/10/05/october-2021-updates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 14:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>October is going to be a great month here at Liberty! Before we get too far in, I want to highlight a few things for you: October 6 – This Wednesday is the first Wednesday night after the Marriage series. We have a number of new groups starting and continue to have fun programs planned...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/05/october-2021-updates/">October 2021 Updates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>October is going to be a great month here at Liberty! Before we get too far in, I want to highlight a few things for you:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>October 6 – This Wednesday</strong> is the first Wednesday night after the Marriage series. We have a number of <strong>new groups starting</strong> and continue to have <strong>fun programs</strong> planned for your <strong>kids and students.</strong> There is something for the whole family. If you are looking to get involved in a group, this is a great opportunity! You can <a href="/groups/finder/">click here</a> to see the different groups that are available.</li>
<li><strong>October 23-30 – </strong>The last week of October is our <strong>757 Strong</strong> We will focus on loving our community through a variety of service projects. You can participate as a group or an individual and you can find more information <a href="/757strong/">here.</a></li>
<li><strong>October 29- November 6</strong> – We have a <strong>team that will be serving in Morocco</strong> at the end of the month. Please be praying for final preparations, for travel logistics, for the missionaries they will be partnering with, and ultimately that doors would be opened for the gospel.</li>
<li><strong>October 31 –</strong> This year, Halloween falls on a Sunday. Liberty Kids is hosting <strong>Candy Palooza!</strong> It will be a great opportunity to invite our friends and neighbors to church. Kids can wear their costume and they will receive a bag of candy. The purpose is to share the gospel!</li>
</ul>
<p>One of our goals at Liberty is to help each person Know God, Find Community, Serve People, and Leave a Legacy. We know God by spending time in the Word and time in prayer. We find community by gathering together and growing together. We serve people by loving the church and loving the community. We leave a legacy by going on mission and giving to the mission. I love that each of the events above is tied directly to that mission. And, if you want to learn more about how you can personally know God, find community, serve people, and leave a legacy, our <strong>Life Track class is coming up November 14.</strong> You can go ahead and <a href="/lifetrack/">sign up here.</a></p>
<p>The reason we do what we do is to change lives, communities, and the world for Jesus Christ. Please be praying that God would use you and use our church to do just that!</p>
<p>Tammy and I are looking forward to all that’s ahead and we hope you are too.</p>
<p>The best is yet to come!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/10/05/october-2021-updates/">October 2021 Updates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Are Some Things That Will Help Me Live a Victorious Christian Life? – Colossians 3:14-17</title>
		<link>/2021/09/27/blog-victoriuschristianlife/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pastor Grant Ethridge]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 20:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Colossians]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As Christians, there are certain things we need to put off and certain things we need to put on. We read this last week at the beginning of Colossians 3. Paul is telling the Colossians how they can live a victorious Christian life. This thought continues as we pick up in verse 14: “Above all,...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/09/27/blog-victoriuschristianlife/">What Are Some Things That Will Help Me Live a Victorious Christian Life? – Colossians 3:14-17</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Christians, there are certain things we need to put off and certain things we need to put on. We read this last week at the beginning of Colossians 3. Paul is telling the Colossians how they can live a victorious Christian life. This thought continues as we pick up in verse 14: “Above all, put on love, which is the perfect bond of unity.” When a person believes in Jesus for salvation, God puts him in the Body, the Church. The body has variety and diversity, but we must work in unity. The devil knows a house divided against itself cannot stand. Above all that Paul has mentioned here, we are called to love. Why? The world will know we are God’s disciples by our love (Jn. 13:35). God is love and we love because He first loved us.</p>
<p><strong>The Peace of Christ</strong></p>
<p>Paul continues, “And let the peace of Christ, to which you were also called in one body, rule your hearts. And be thankful” (v. 15). The peace <em>of</em> God is not the same as peace <em>with</em> God. Peace with God happens at salvation (Rom. 5:1, Col. 1:20). In Philippians 4:7, Paul describes the peace of God as something that surpasses all understanding and that guards our hearts and minds. Peace is the opposite of worry. Worry means to pull apart. Peace means to join together. “Rule” is an athletic term meaning to umpire or referee. What is ruling in your heart? Is it anger or bitterness? Discontentment or jealousy? <em>God is always more concerned about what is going on within you than what is going on around you.</em> God wants to bring peace to your chaos. When you feel like your whole world is unraveling and you feel like you are falling apart, the peace of God will guard your emotions. I love the quote that says, “<em>When you find a Bible falling apart it probably belongs to someone who is not.”  </em></p>
<p><strong>The Word of Christ</strong></p>
<p>“Let the word of Christ dwell richly among you, in all wisdom teaching and admonishing one another through psalms, hymns, and spiritual songs, singing to God with gratitude in your hearts” (v. 16). Jesus is the Word of God. <em>You would not know the living Word apart from the written Word. All scripture is God-breathed. </em>“Dwell” means to settle down. It literally means to be at home. Do you live in the Word and stay in the Word? God’s Word should be welcomed in every area of our lives. Instead of dwelling on the <em>past</em> or on your <em>problem</em>s, dwell on the <em>promises</em> of God’s word.  How? <em>Read</em> God’s word daily. <em>Hear</em> God’s word in sermons and in songs. <em>Study</em> God’s word. <em>Memorize</em> God’s word. <em>Treasure</em> God’s word. Ultimately, <em>obey</em> God’s word. Be a doer of the word and not a hearer only. And <em>share</em> God’s word. The Bible is morning manna, living water, and it is milk and meat through which we taste and see the Lord is good. When making a decision, our first question should be, “What does the Bible say?” One way we teach and learn the word of God is through worship. We sing to God, but we also sing to admonish ourselves and one another. The only thing God has exalted above His name is His Word (Ps. 138:2).</p>
<p><strong>The Name of Christ</strong></p>
<p>“And whatever you do, in word or in deed, do everything in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him” (v. 17). Whatever you do, do your best for Jesus. Before you do something ask this question, “Would Jesus put His name on it?” A person’s name is so important. What do you write on a legal document or on a check? Your name. There is authority in your name. A President or Governor signs bills into law with the signature of his name. Jesus told us to pray in the name of Jesus (Jn. 14:13-14). There is power in the name of Jesus. That is why we pray in the name of Jesus. We praise the name of Jesus. We will be persecuted and hated for His name’s sake (Acts 5:40-41). The reason we live is to make much of His name. Acts 2:21 says, “Whoever calls on the name of the Lord shall be saved.” Acts 4:12 says, “There is salvation in no one else, for there is no other name under heaven given to people by which we must be saved.”</p>
<p>As you seek to live the Christian life victoriously, ask God to help you love Him and others. Ask for His peace to rule in your heart and for His word to dwell in you. Finally, whatever you do, do it all in the name of Jesus.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/09/27/blog-victoriuschristianlife/">What Are Some Things That Will Help Me Live a Victorious Christian Life? – Colossians 3:14-17</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Liberty Live Church</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
